Chudelkin: I SWEAR, MILADY,
I WILL NOT LET YOU DOWN.
HUP!
I AM RESOLUTE AND ENERGIZED!
I AM MOTIVATED,
AND I AM INVINCIBLE!
SYSTEM CALL!
GENERATE THERMAL ELEMENT!
( all gasp )
♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ PROUD OF MYSELF ♪
♪
( flames whooshing )
( all gasp )
Alice: I HAD NO IDEA
HE COULD CONJURE SUCH SPELLS.
I UNDERESTIMATED HIM.
THAT FIRE GIANT IS A BEING
MADE ENTIRELY OF MAGIC.
MY FLOWERS CANNOT DESTROY
SUCH A THING,
AND I DOUBT THEY COULD
HOLD IT OFF FOR VERY LONG.
Kirito: HOW LONG? I MEAN,
WE DON’T NEED THAT MUCH TIME,
JUST ENOUGH
TO GET UP CLOSE TO CHUDELKIN.
Alice: FOR TEN SECONDS, NO MORE,
PERHAPS LESS THAN THAT.
STILL, YOU’RE RIGHT. I’LL DRAW
ITS ATTENTION WHILE YOU ATTACK,
BUT DO NOT ADVANCE TOO FAR.
THAT IS WHAT THE PONTIFEX
IS WAITING FOR.
Kirito: TEN...
Eugeo: SECONDS?
( both grunt )
( Alice gasps )
( chorus vocalizing )
SWARM, MY FLOWERS!
( gasping )
( Kirito gasps )
♪
( growls )
( woman vocalizing )
GO FOR HER EYES.
Eugeo: YOU GOT IT.
SYSTEM CALL.
DISCHARGE!
Chudelkin: NO, NO, NO, NO!
WATCH OUT, YOUR EMINENCE!
( Administrator sighs )
( Chudelkin laughs )
( Kirito grunts )
( growling )
Eugeo: WHAT’S HE DOING?
( Kirito yelling )
Chudelkin: EH? OHH!
( Kirito yells )
( Chudelkin gasps )
( gags )
( screaming )
( gagging )
EMINENCE.
( plops )
( gasps )
Eugeo: KIRITO.
( Kirito gasping )
Administrator: WELL,
THAT WAS RATHER ANTICLIMACTIC.
I DID GAIN SOME USEFUL
INFORMATION FROM IT, THOUGH,
SO IT’S NOT A TOTAL LOSS.
HOW UNSIGHTLY.
Alice: HEARTLESS CREATURE.
Administrator:
SO, IRREGULAR BOY,
I THINK I’VE FIGURED OUT
THE MYSTERY OF YOU.
AT FIRST, I THOUGHT
I COULDN’T SEE YOUR PROPERTIES
BECAUSE YOU WERE UNREGISTERED,
AN ILLEGITIMATE BIRTH,
BUT I WAS WRONG.
YOU’RE HUMAN,
NOT FROM THIS WORLD.
YOU’RE FROM THE OTHER SIDE.
AREN’T YOU?
( Eugeo gasps )
- Kirito: I AM.
- ( Eugeo gasps )
Kirito: SO, WHAT?
YOU DON’T FEEL
THREATENED BY ME, DO YOU?
I GOT THE SAME AUTHORITY LEVEL
AS EVERYONE ELSE.
IT’S NOWHERE NEAR AS HIGH
AS YOURS, THAT’S FOR SURE,
ADMINISTRATOR.
SORRY. QUINELLA.
( Administrator laughs )
OH, THAT LITTLE IMP.
SHE’S FILLED YOUR HEAD
WITH RIDICULOUS STORIES.
WELL, BOY, WHAT ARE YOU
DOING IN MY WORLD?
I DOUBT YOU JUST STUMBLED IN
OUT OF CURIOSITY.
Kirito: YOU’RE RIGHT. I DIDN’T.
YOUR WORLD’S
GONNA END REAL SOON,
AND IT’S GONNA BE
ALL YOUR FAULT.
( Administrator laughs )
I’M SORRY. WHAT?
ARE YOU SAYING I’LL DESTROY IT?
Kirito: PRETTY MUCH.
THE DARK TERRITORY WILL INVADE.
THAT’S WHY YOU MADE
THE INTEGRITY KNIGHTS,
TO STOP IT, BUT YOUR FAITH
IN THEM’S YOUR MISTAKE.
THEY WON’T BE ENOUGH.
( Administrator laughs )
THAT SOUNDS
EXACTLY LIKE SOMETHING
THAT LITTLE BRAT WOULD SAY.
HOW PITIFUL,
BOTH HER, FOR BEING SO DESPERATE
TO HAVE ME EXPELLED,
AND YOU, FOR BEING SO GULLIBLE.
Alice: MADAM PONTIFEX,
IF I MAY,
THE ARMY OF THE DARK
HAS GROWN RAPIDLY.
IF THEY INVADE NOW,
THE CURRENT NUMBER OF KNIGHTS
CANNOT WITHSTAND IT.
THE COMMANDER BELIEVED SO,
AS DID VICE COMMANDER FANATIO
AND I, I AS WELL.
WHAT IS YOUR PLAN NOW THAT
THE ORDER OF KNIGHTS IS NO MORE?
DO YOU THINK YOU ALONE
CAN PROTECT THE EMPIRE?
BUT WHAT ANGERS ME MORE
THAN YOUR HUBRIS,
YOU HAVE STOLEN
US KNIGHTS FROM OUR PARENTS,
FROM WIVES AND HUSBANDS,
BROTHERS AND SISTERS.
YOU SEALED AWAY
OUR MEMORIES OF THEM
AND REPLACED THEM WITH LIES
OF BEING SUMMONED
FROM A NONEXISTENT HEAVEN!
PONTIFEX, COULD YOU NOT TRUST US
TO BE LOYAL TO YOU
AND RESPECT YOUR AUTHORITY?
WERE WE SUCH A THREAT TO YOU,
YOU HAD TO SUBMIT US
TO SUCH A MONSTROUS RITUAL
AND FORCE OUR SOULS
INTO OBEDIENCE?!
( Eugeo grunts )
Administrator:
I DO TRUST YOU, THOUGH.
IN FACT, I LOVE YOU.
THE PIETY MODULE
INSTALLED IN YOU KNIGHTS
IS PROOF OF MY LOVE,
A GIFT FROM ME TO YOU ALL.
WHY, THIS LITTLE THING
FREES YOU FROM THE WORRY
AND PAIN OF NORMAL FOLK.
YOU ARE MY BEAUTIFUL DOLLS,
BEAUTIFUL FOR ALL ETERNITY.
Alice: OUT OF ALL
THE KNIGHTS, UNC--
COMMANDER BERCOULI HAS
SHOWN YOU THE DEEPEST LOYALTY,
BUT YOU DO NOT KNOW THE MAN,
EVEN THOUGH HE HAS SERVED YOU
FAITHFULLY FOR 300 LONG YEARS.
DO YOU THINK HE DID NOT SUFFER
ONCE IN ALL THAT TIME?
DID YOU NOT KNOW OF THE PAIN
HE CARRIED IN HIS HEART?
ARE YOU THAT OBLIVIOUS?!
Administrator:
YOU THINK SO LITTLE OF ME.
OF COURSE I KNEW.
THESE THINGS YOU SPEAK OF
DIDN’T START BOTHERING BERCOULI
RECENTLY, THOUGH.
HE BROUGHT THEM UP AGES AGO.
A CENTURY, I THINK?
YES, ABOUT THAT, GIVE OR TAKE.
I COULDN’T WATCH HIM BROOD
OVER SUCH TRIVIALITIES,
SO I FIXED HIM,
RESET HIM, TO BE MORE SPECIFIC.
( laughs )
AND HE WAS NOT THE ONLY ONE.
I RESET EVERY KNIGHT
MORE THAN A CENTURY OLD.
ALL OF THEIR PAINFUL MEMORIES
AND TROUBLING THOUGHTS
WERE WIPED AWAY.
DON’T YOU WORRY, ALICE.
I’LL OVERLOOK
YOUR TRANSGRESSIONS
AND ERASE ALL THE THOUGHTS
THAT MAKE YOU SO MISERABLE, TOO.
BEFORE YOU KNOW IT, YOU’LL GO
BACK TO BEING MY PUPPET
AND HAVE NO NEED TO THINK.
( Eugeo gasps )
( flesh creaks )
Alice: YOU ARE CORRECT.
RIGHT NOW, I FEEL
ENOUGH SADNESS AND PAIN
TO TEAR MY HEART TO PIECES.
HOWEVER, I CHOOSE TO EMBRACE IT.
I DO NOT WISH TO ERASE
WHAT I HAVE NEVER FELT BEFORE.
THIS PAIN SERVES A PURPOSE.
IT REMINDS ME WHAT I AM,
A HUMAN BEING
AND NOT A PUPPET KNIGHT.
MADAM PONTIFEX, I DO
NOT WANT YOUR SO-CALLED LOVE,
AND I DO NOT NEED YOU
TO FIX ME!
Administrator:
I’M SAD TO HEAR THAT.
UNFORTUNATELY,
WHAT YOU WANT DOESN’T MATTER.
AS SOON AS I RESYNTHESIZE YOU--
AND I WILL--THE PESKY FEELINGS
THAT TROUBLE YOU NOW
WILL BE ERASED COMPLETELY.
Kirito: KINDA LIKE WHAT YOU DID
TO YOURSELF WAY BACK WHEN,
HUH, QUINELLA?
Administrator:
WATCH IT, LITTLE BOY.
DREDGING UP THE PAST
IS CONSIDERED QUITE RUDE.
Kirito: WHY? YOU SCARED
THE TRUTH WILL COME OUT?
NO ONE’S GOT THE POWER
TO ERASE THE PAST, NOT EVEN YOU.
YOU WERE BORN A HUMAN
AND RAISED A HUMAN.
AND NO MATTER
HOW MUCH POWER YOU GOT,
THAT’S ONE THING
YOU CAN’T CHANGE, CAN YOU?
Administrator:
I’M NOT QUITE SURE
WHAT YOU’RE GETTING AT,
LITTLE BOY FROM THE OUTER WORLD.
Kirito: ALL YOU WANT
IS TO BE A GOD,
BUT YOU CAN NEVER BE A GOD,
’CAUSE YOU’RE HUMAN.
BEING HUMAN
MEANS YOU MAKE MISTAKES,
AND YOU MADE A BIG ONE.
AT THIS POINT, THERE’S NOTHING
YOU CAN DO TO FIX IT.
YOU GOT
LESS INTEGRITY KNIGHTS NOW.
IF THE DARK TERRITORY INVADES,
WHO’S GONNA STOP ’EM?
THEY’LL DESTROY EVERYTHING.
Administrator:
AND WHO WAS THE ONE
WHO CORRUPTED
SOME OF MY BEST KNIGHTS?
THAT WAS YOU, BOY.
Kirito: IF YOU’RE
ALL THAT’S LEFT AFTER THIS,
MAYBE YOU CAN START OVER
WITH A CLEAN SLATE.
MAYBE THAT’S WHAT
YOU ALWAYS WANTED.
THING IS, IT AIN’T GONNA GO
THE WAY YOU WANT IT.
ON THE OTHER SIDE,
THERE’S THE PEOPLE
WHO CREATED THIS WORLD
AND HAVE FINAL SAY
OVER WHAT HAPPENS TO IT.
WHEN THEY SEE
THE HUMAN EMPIRE FALL,
THEY’LL THINK,
"OH, WELL, THAT DIDN’T WORK.
I GUESS WE’LL START OVER."
AND THEN ONE OF THEM
WILL PUSH A BUTTON,
AND EVERYTHING’LL DISAPPEAR,
THE MOUNTAINS, THE RIVERS...
THE TOWNS...
EVERY PERSON HERE, AND YOU.
THEY’LL ERASE IT ALL
IN THE BLINK OF AN EYE.
( Eugeo gasps )
Administrator: POINT TAKEN.
BUT I HAVE A FEELING THE SAME
GOES FOR YOUR WORLD, TOO.
YOU MUST HAVE A CREATOR.
DOES YOUR KIND GRAPPLE
WITH THE THOUGHT
OF LIVING UNDER THE WHIM
OF A HIGHER POWER AS WELL?
DO YOU STRIVE TO PLEASE
THIS BEING, OBEYING ITS LAWS,
HOPING IT WON’T TIRE OF YOU
AND WIPE YOU OUT?
( Kirito gasps )
Administrator: I WOULD BE
SHOCKED IF THAT WERE THE CASE.
AS YOU SAY,
YOUR KIND CREATED OUR WORLD,
AND, IF WE FAIL THEM, THEY
WOULD DELETE US WITHOUT A CARE.
IF THAT IS HOW
YOUR KIND TREAT US, BOY,
THEN YOU DO NOT HAVE
THE RIGHT TO CRITICIZE ME.
I REJECT THEIR AUTHORITY.
I WILL NOT PANDER
TO SELF-PROCLAIMED GODS,
GROVELING FOR THE RIGHT
TO CONTINUE EXISTING.
I REFUTE THEM ALL.
I EXIST FOR ONE REASON ALONE,
TO RULE OVER ALL IN THIS WORLD.
THAT SINGULAR DESIRE IS WHAT
DRIVES ME AND GIVES ME LIFE.
MY LEGS ARE FOR CLIMBING
OVER OTHERS TO GREATER HEIGHTS,
NOT TO BEND AT THE KNEE
IN SUBJUGATION!
( Eugeo gasps )
( Kirito grunts )
AND THEN WHAT?!
ARE YOU GONNA SIT BACK AND LET
THE HUMAN EMPIRE GET DESTROYED?
ARE YOU GONNA WATCH
EVERYTHING BURN,
ALONE ON YOUR TOKEN THRONE,
A QUEEN WITH NO ONE TO RULE?!
Administrator: ON THE CONTRARY.
I WILL NOT ALLOW YOUR KIND
TO RESET THE UNDERWORLD,
NOR WILL I ALLOW
THE FINAL STRESS TEST
TO RUN ITS COURSE, EITHER.
I’VE PREPARED A NEW SACRED ART
TO COUNTER THAT, IN FACT.
SO BE HONORED.
YOU WILL BE WITNESSES,
THE FIRST TO TEST MY CREATION.
Kirito: WHAT CREATION?
Administrator:
THE KNIGHTS WERE A STOPGAP,
AND THEY HAVE SERVED
THEIR PURPOSE WELL.
THE MILITARY FORCE I REQUIRE
SHOULD NOT THINK
OR FEEL OR REMEMBER.
IN BATTLE,
THOSE ARE DISTRACTIONS.
MY PERFECT SOLDIER
RELENTLESSLY MASSACRES
WHATEVER ENEMY STANDS BEFORE IT.
ULTIMATELY, WHAT I REQUIRE
IS NOT HUMAN.
WAKE, AND DESTROY YOUR ENEMY,
MY FAITHFUL SERVANT,
MY SOULLESS EXTERMINATOR!
RELEASE RECOLLECTION!
♪
Eugeo: WH-WHAT’S SHE DONE?!
Alice: IMPOSSIBLE.
( Kirito gasps )
DISCHARGE!
( energy humming )
( Eugeo gasps )
Alice: THIS CAN’T BE.
ALL THOSE WEAPONS?
USING PERFECT WEAPON CONTROL
ON 30 AT ONCE
SHOULD BE IMPOSSIBLE,
EVEN FOR THE PONTIFEX.
IT VIOLATES THE SACRED ARTS.
( Administrator giggles )
( laughs )
( sighs )
AT LONG LAST,
THE POWER I HAVE SOUGHT,
OFFENSIVE MIGHT WITH NO EQUAL,
A SOLDIER
THAT WILL FIGHT FOREVER.
NOW, WHAT SHALL I CALL IT?
I KNOW. THE SWORD GOLEM!
Kirito: NO WAY.
IT’S A WALKING SWORD.
♪
Administrator:
EACH ONE OF ITS BLADES
HAS THE PRIORITY LEVEL
OF A DIVINE OBJECT.
I STRETCHED
MY PRECIOUS MEMORY CAPACITY
TO THE LIMIT TO CREATE THIS,
THE ULTIMATE WEAPON.
DO YOU THINK YOU CAN DEFEAT IT?
( Kirito shudders )
( Alice gasping )
( Eugeo gasping )
Administrator: NOW GO FORTH,
AND FIGHT, MY GOLEM.
GO AND ANNIHILATE YOUR ENEMIES!
♪
( clanging )
( Eugeo gasping )
( Alice yelling )
( Eugeo gasps )
( Alice gasping )
( Kirito yelling )
( gags )
( wall clattering )
♪
( gasping )
( Eugeo shuddering )
( Administrator laughing )
( clangs )
Kirito: EU-EUGEO...
Charlotte: EUGEO,
USE YOUR DAGGER!
( Eugeo gasps )
Charlotte:
STAB THE LEVITATING DISC!
Eugeo: HUH?
Charlotte:
I’LL BUY YOU SOME TIME.
HURRY!
♪
( hisses )
( magic humming )
( Eugeo gasping )
Charlotte:
THANK GOODNESS. HE MADE IT.
I’M HAPPY I GOT
TO FIGHT WITH YOU
ONE LA...
( pieces clatter )
( Administrator chuckles )
( Kirito groans )
♪
( gasps )
Cardinal: EH?
( Kirito groans )
Alice: KIRITO...
WHO IS THIS PERSON?
Kirito: SHE’S CARDINAL.
SHE’S THE GOOD PONTIFEX
OF THIS WORLD.
200 YEARS AGO,
SHE FOUGHT ADMINISTRATOR,
BUT SHE HAD TO GO INTO HIDING.
SHE SAVED EUGEO AND ME AND
GUIDED US INTO THE CATHEDRAL.
SHE WANTS TO HELP.
NO ONE LOVES THIS WORLD
MORE THAN HER.
Alice: I DON’T DOUBT IT.
I TRUST THE WARMTH OF HER POWER.
THANK YOU FOR HEALING ME,
MILADY.
Cardinal: MM.
( rings clinking )
YOU STUBBORN FOOL.
DID I NOT RELIEVE YOU
OF YOUR DUTIES?
DID I NOT THANK YOU
FOR ALL YOUR HARD WORK?
WHY COULDN’T YOU
JUST STAY ON YOUR BOOKSHELF?
Kirito: I’M SORRY.
DID SHE HAVE A FLUCTLIGHT, TOO?
Cardinal: NO.
TO BORROW A TERM
FROM YOUR WORLD,
CHARLOTTE WAS LIKE AN NPC.
Kirito: W-WAIT. WHAT?
BUT SHE--
SHE RISKED HER LIFE TO SAVE ME.
THAT’S NOT SOMETHING
AN NPC’D DO.
I MEAN, IF SHE DIDN’T
HAVE A SOUL, THEN--
Cardinal: THIS CHILD
HAD BEEN ALIVE FOR 200 YEARS.
SHE WAS MY CONSTANT COMPANION,
AND SHE WATCHED OVER
A NUMBER OF PEOPLE FOR ME.
FOR THE PAST TWO YEARS,
SHE WAS WITH YOU.
AFTER SPENDING
ALL THAT TIME WITH SOMEONE,
ONE DOESN’T NEED
A FLUCTLIGHT TO CARE.
EVEN IF THE NATURE
OF AN INTELLIGENCE
IS JUST A COLLECTION
OF INPUT AND OUTPUT DATA,
IT IS STILL POSSIBLE FOR IT
TO HAVE A TRUE SOUL WITHIN
AND, IN SOME CASES, LOVE.
A CONCEPT
YOU’LL NEVER UNDERSTAND,
AS LONG AS YOU LIVE!
ADMINISTRATOR,
YOU WRETCHED WOMAN!
( Administrator laughing )
( chorus vocalizing )
Singer: ♪ OH, EVERYTHING
TURNS TO ASH, TO ASH ♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ AND EVERYTHING
TURNS TO DUST, TO DUST ♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ FORGET-ME-NOT ♪